Maryam **Mohammadi**

% https://mohammadi-maryam.github.io

@ maryam.mohammadi@uni-bielefeld.de

@ maryam.mohammadi@uni-konstanz.de

Research Interests: My research interests are semantics, pragmatics and experimental studies, where theories can meet the real data. I mostly worked on polar questions and answers, bias, speech acts, and attitude predicates. I am also interested in programming to implement and develop algorithms from natural language to artificial languages.

EDUCATION

2024 Post-doc at Bielefeld University (Germany)

2024 Ph.D. Linguistics, Konstanz University (Germany)

Dissertation: Bias Conditions in Polar Questions and Answers: A study of Bias Effects in Farsi

2015 MA. Linguistics, Allame University (Iran)

Thesis: "var" Prefix in Farsi, a Cognitive Study in Word Formation

2013 BA. English Translation, Qazvin University (Iran)

2006 Associate Degree, Computer Science, Azad University (Iran)

OTHER CERTIFICATES

ESSLLI Summer School

2021

> Modules: Commitment-based pragmatics (Bart Geurts), Dynamic inquisitive semantics (Jakub Dotlačil and Floris Roelofsen), Intensionalism and Propositionalism in Linguistic Semantics (Kristina Liefke and Ede Zimmermann)

Project Management Workshop

2020

> Modules: Classic and Agile project planning, Team works, Self-management, Software Trello.

DGfS Berlin Summer School

2019

> Modules: Questions (Maribel Romero), Speech Acts (Manfred Krifka), Statistics with R (Nicole Gotzner), Alternative Sets (Clemens Steiner-Mayr), Viewing Experimental Pragmatics from a Cognitive Science perspective (Ira Noveck).

Publications

Mohammadi, M. Non-Canonical Questions in Farsi, to appear in The Oxford Handbook of Non-Canonical to appear Questions, Oxford University Press.

Mohammadi, M., Koev, T. Speaker Attitudes Predict Epistemic Biases in Polar Questions: Evidence from Farsi, to appear to appear in the proceedings of West Cost Conference of Formal Linguistics (WCCFL) 42, Berkeley University.

2024 Mohammadi, M. Bias Conditions in Polar Questions and Answers: A study of Bias Effects in Farsi, PhD Dissertation, Konstanz University.

2024 Mohammadi, M., Romero, M. Polar Particles in Farsi: Sensitivity to the Scoreboard Model of Discourse, In the proceedings of Sinn und Bedeutun (SuB) 28.

2023 Mohammadi, M. Bias effect on response preference, In the proceedings of Chicago Linguistic Society (CLS)

2023 Mohammadi, M. mage as a bias particle in interrogatives, In the proceedings of Inquisitiveness Below and Beyond the Sentence Boundary (InqBnB) 4 workshop, IWCS Conference.

Mohammadi, M. Which stress is on response particles? An empirical study, In the proceedings of Linguistic 2023 Society of America (LSA) 8.

2022 Mohammadi, M. A unified account of polar particles in Farsi, In the proceedings of Linguistic Society of America (LSA) 7.

2020 Koev, T., Bill, C., & Mohammadi, M. Believe is strong but subjective: Experimental evidence from hedging. In the proceedings of Sinn und Bedeutung (SuB) 25.

- Mohammadi, M. A Contrastive Analysis of Speech Act Conditionals as Indirect Answers in English and Farsi, Cambridge scholars publication.
- 2018 Hesse, Ch., Mohammadi, M., Langner, M., Fischer, J., Benz, A. & Klabunde, R. Communicating an understanding of intention: Speech act conditionals and modified numerals in a Q/A system. In the proceedings of SemDial 22.

in progress Polar response particles in Farsi: Lexical ambiguity.

PRESENTATIONS

- 2024 Speaker Attitudes Predict Epistemic Biases in Polar Questions: Evidence from Farsi, WCCFL 42, Barkley Uni-
- 2023 Polar Particles in Farsi: Sensitivity to the Scoreboard Model of Discourse, Semantics Workshop at the University of Massachusetts (Amherst).
- 2023 Polar Particles in Farsi: Sensitivity to the Scoreboard Model of Discourse, SuB 28, Bochum, Germany.
- 2023 'mage' as a bias particle in interrogatives, IWCS, InqBnB workshop, Nancy, France.
- 2023 Bias effect of response preference, CLS 59, Chicago University (poster presentation).
- 2023 mage: a Bias Sensitive Discourse Particle, NACIL 3, University of California, Los Angeles.
- 2023 Which Stress is on Response Particles? An empirical study, LSA Conference, Denver, Colorado.
- 2022 Which stress is on PRPs? SemDial 26, Technological University of Dublin, Ireland (poster presentation).
- A unified account of polar particles in Farsi, LSA Conference, Washington DC. 2022
- 2020 Believe is strong but subjective: Experimental evidence from hedging, SuB 25 (with Koev and Bill).
- 2018 A Contrastive Analysis of Speech Act Conditionals as Indirect Answers in English and Farsi, CoCoLaC conference, Helsinki University, Finland.
- 2018 From learning user types to generating biscuit conditionals, ComPrag Workshop, Bochum University.
- Communicating an understanding of intention: Speech act conditionals and modified numerals in a Q/A 2018 system, SemDial 22, Aix-en-Provence, France (with Judith Fischer).
- Communicating an understanding of intention: Speech act conditionals and modified numerals in a Q/A 2018 system, DGfS Conference, Stuttgart University, Germany.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UMass (Amherst)

Visiting Scholar

2023

> Visiting the University of Massachusetts (Amherst) during the fall semester.

Konstanz Uni.

2020-2021

- > Tutoring course "Core Components of Language (B)", including syntax, semantics, pragmatics.
- > Tutoring course "Pragmatics I".

Ruhr University

2017-2019

Research assistant

- > Running a python application to generate indirect answers with speech act (/biscuit) conditionals.
- > Designing a decision-making model, using Bayesian probability.
- > Running a series of experiments in Amazon Mechanical Turk to find out English speakers' attitude towards the structure.
- > Data analysis with R.
- > Presenting the result in different conferences and workshops.

Chargoon Co.

Software developer

2015-2017

- > Developing a web-based software in HR system.
- > Team work for designing new features based on customers' requirements

Part time jobs 2010-2017

Programmer and Teacher

- > During my student years, I engaged in programming for various software companies.
- > I served as an English language teacher in several language institutes.



R&D I like to work on new topics and develop them with experimental studies. I conducted several experiments

in different frameworks e.g. Amazon MTurk, Testable, SurveyMonkey, as well as working on audio recording.

Data analysis I have experience in different statistical data analysis (e.g. lmer, GAMMs).

Programming R, Praat, LaTeX, Python, C#, ASP.NET, Delphi, WordPress, HTML, XML, CSS, SQL, Access

</> </> LANGUAGES

• Farsi : Native • English : Fluent • German : B2

66 References

Prof. Manfred Krifka

Leibniz-Centre General Linguistics (ZAS)

@ krifka@leibniz-zas.de

**** +49 30 20192 403

Prof. Maribel Romero

Department of Linguistics University of Konstanz

@ maribel.romero@uni-konstanz.de

4 +49 7531 882720

Dr. Todor Koev

Department of Linguistics University of Konstanz

@ todor.koev@uni-konstanz.de

**** +49 1573 2647920